Dinank Bista

3527093307 bista.dinank@gmail.com . https://github.com/danebista

Summary

Build MVS(Managed Vaccine Software), an online portal that is being used by the city of Seattleto provide COVID vaccines. 411 thousand vaccines provided till date. https://www.signetic.com/

Worked with Microsoft Seattle to design an ETL for transferring School Information System(SIS) data of high schools into the database of Microsoft.

Designed the data architecture for transfer of millions of data from legacy Client Track system to the Microsoft Dynamics software solution for Hopelink. https://www.hopelink.org/

Published a journal paper in the International Journal of Social Science(IJASS)

Experience

University of Florida

Gainesville, USA

Graduate Research Assistant at the Init Lab

Currently involved in two funded projects MyTrack and SatC

Fuse Machines Inc New York / Kathmandu

Service oriented software company building world class solutions

Software Engineer Level 2

September, 2021 – Present

Architecture and Backend Design Using AWS Amplify, AWS lambda resolvers and Dynamo DB.

Leapfrog Technologies Inc

Seattle / Kathmandu

Service oriented software company building world class solutions

Software Engineer

July, 2020 - September 2021

Improved the entire code base. Legacy frontend code improvements using redux, redux saga, hooks, HOC patterns, styled components

Architecture and ETL flow development. Data oriented development using MS-SQL, system flows and processes.

Data staging and migration in Node JS

C# Developer(Middleware design/ Plugins) and Vanilla JS Developer(Webresources)

Associate Software Engineer

September, 2019 – July, 2020

Designed Multiple Pages in ReactJS
Api endpoints using NodeJS
C# Developer(Middleware design/ Plugins)
Vanilla JS Developer(Webresources)

Intern

July, 2019 – September, 2019

HTML/CSS, Vanilla JS, React JS, Node JS, Polymer JS, Algorithms implementation(Goal based path finding algorithm)

Sagarmatha Engineering College

Computer Science Information Technology College in Nepal

Programming Skill Development Instructor

February 2020 — May 2020

Kathmandu, Nepal

Education

Ph.D. in Human Centered Computing/ MS in CS, Gainesville, Florida Ongoing program at the University of Florida

Bachelors of Computer Engineering, Kathmandu, 2015-2019 A four year bachelors program on computer engineering

Kathmandu University, BCE, Computer, 2015 - 2019

Science Degree (Grade 11-12), Kathmandu, 2013-2015 A two year high school science degree 82.2 percent out of 100 Top 2% across entire college

Prasadi Academy, HSEB, Science, 2013 - 2015

Research

International Journal of Advanced Social Science: Social Networking Application Adaptability to Fitts' Law

Additional

Worked at a research assistant for two months at the IT Park of Nepal on the project "Grammar Checker for Devanagari(Nepali language)"

eceived \$2000 from Employees Provident Fund (EPF Nepal) for excellent grades at secondary level. eceived financial assistance from the Government of Nepal during bachelors. Hackathon Event Manager - IT Meet v8.0

Documentation Lead - IT Meet v8.0

Unofficial Transcript

Fall 2022						^
Jniversity of Florida						
College Herbert Wertheim College	e of Engineering		Level Graduate			
Term GPA 3.66	Hours Carried 6.00		Hours Earned 9.00	Grade Points Earned 21.99		
Course (Class)	Course Title	Grade	Credit Attempted	Credit Earned	Credit for GPA	
CEN5728 (24898)	Ux Design	Α	3.00	3.00	3	
CIS6935 (22939)	HCC Graduate Seminar	S	1.00	1.00	-	
CIS7979 (11306)	Advanced Research	S	2.00	2.00		
COT5405 (12445)	Analys of Algorithms	B+	3.00	3.00	3	